SISHIR BHATTARAI

Herriman, UT 84020 | 704-806-5842 | sishir.bhattarai@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sishir-bhattarai | https://github.com/sishirbhattarai

SUMMARY

Cloud Engineer

Passionate IT Server and Cloud Support Engineer with knowledge of Dell EMC Storage, Linux, DNS, DHCP, Routing, Active Directory, Servers, IP address, Microsoft Azure and Hyper-V, and ensuring security of Company's IT network and Servers. Experienced and results-oriented with proven abilities in developing positive relationships with clients and coworkers. Highly motivated and energetic, I strive to ensure that all tasks are successfully accomplished on time. Interested in a technical opportunity with a company where exceptional organizational, computer and customer service skills will be required.

Single Scope Background Investigation Critical thinking		Strong work ethics
JQUERY	HTML, CSS, JS	Problem Solving
DNS Configuration	Attention to Detail	Project Management
DHCP Configuration	Time management	Communication and Collaboration
Strategic Planning	Teamwork	Decision-making skills
VIPs	NAT	Load Balancer

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Utah, Full Stack Web Developer, Salt Lake City, UT

Sept 2020-Present

Enrolled in intensive, 24 weeks coding bootcamp program that includes both frontend and backend academics to become full stack web-developer. The Marketable Skills that I am learning are HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, and more.

- Developed, tested, and deployed multiple applications using HTML, CSS, JS, JQUERY.
 - a) Weather Dashboard Application: The user story for this application is, as a traveler I want to see the weather outlook for multiple cities so that I can plan a trip accordingly. For more information, click my Github link below.

 Live Deployed Link: https://sishirbhattarai.github.io/Sishir-Weather-Dashboard/
 - **b) Password Generator Application:** The user story for this application is, AS AN employee with access to sensitive data I WANT to randomly generate a password that meets certain criteria so that I can create a strong password that provides greater security. For more information, click my GitHub link below.

Live Deployed Link: https://sishirbhattarai.github.io/Passowrd-Generator/

- Integrated software components and third-party API to develop users friendly application.
- Worked as a Team to develop a project name Daily Feed which is also pinned on my GitHub profile. This project features MapQuestAPI, GuardianAPI, and WeatherBit API to get the best relevant news and the weather.
 GitHub Project: The user story for this project is, as a user, I need an app which shows current local weather as well as any latest news on searching all in one page. As a user, I want to save news if needed and delete it after saved. For more information about project and its contributors, click my GitHub link below.

Live Deployed Link: https://sishirbhattarai.github.io/DailyFeed/

Troubleshooted, debugged and upgraded existing software

Dell EMC, Elastic Cloud Storage (ECS) Support Engineer, Draper, UT

March 2018-Present

Motivated technical support engineer solved technically complex level of problems meeting Service Level Agreement (SLA) and provided the highest possible customer satisfaction with perfect CSAT score by setting the right expectations and fulfilling commitments.

• Provided technical support involving broad, in-depth product knowledge or in-depth product specialty to internal, domestic and international EMC customers meeting SLA.

Internal Use - Confidential

- Prioritized my work to accomplish the most important and urgent requests first. Maintained a proactive approach to customer happiness, identifying and correcting customer satisfaction concerns before they become problems.
- Took ownership of new cases and escalations via telephone and Web and provided support to enterprise customers and
 partners. Assisted many customers during Data Unavailable events with my Linux skill and using networking tools like ping,
 tracert, and wire shark.
- Assisted S3 clients, LDAP clients, NFS clients, and AD clients to create buckets in the ECS and assisted to integrate with their
 applications.
- Assisted Data Domain clients and Isilon client's issue as these both are integrated with ECS.
- Listened patiently to each client's and user's concerns, figured out exactly what the problem was and calmly helped troubleshoot and solve the problems.
- Communicated with customer via telephone, written correspondence, or electronic service regarding finding solutions for the most technically complex problems. Customer Obsession is my passion which drive me to make our customers experiences easy, insightful and trusted
- Collaborated with management, cross-team and engineering team to resolve technical issues of customers.
- Created Knowledge Base documents for any new issues with its resolution so that issue can be resolved quickly next time.
- Showed Flexibility on work hours schedule whenever business needed me.

Microsoft, Microsoft Software & Systems Academy Participant (MSSA), Lacey, WA

September 2017 – December 2017

I qualified for the Microsoft Software & Systems Academy (MSSA). It is an intensive, full-time, IT boot camp that includes academic and technical training, certification testing and practical exercises aligned to meet urgent industry needs for Information Technology professionals. The program combines college accredited academics and hands-on training, with the goal of preparing transitioning service members (Veterans) for technical opportunities at Microsoft and their partners.

I specialize in Server and Cloud Administration:

- Set up, configured and maintained company networks and system infrastructure; generate system improvements based on business needs.
- Developed and monitored security related policies and guidelines; monitor the implementation of a security infrastructure;
 install and implement security programs.
- Deployed virtual systems and network resources according to specifications based on established guidelines.
- Collaborated with other departments to troubleshoot and resolve network connectivity and stability issues; test networks for weaknesses.
- Implemented Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions.
- Installed and configured Windows Server 2016.

US Army, Senior Supply Manager at Army dining facility, JBLM, WA

Sep 2016 - Jun, 2017

Accomplished measurable results while leading teams in a dynamic, fast-paced environment. Possess a comprehensive background in supply chain and logistics management conducting various operations.

- **Award Winning:** Awarded Best Supply Manager across an organization of 300 people due to implementation of process in supply team that increased record keeping accuracy. Process adopted by entire organization.
- Managed and oversaw \$2M+ worth of properties, rations, supplies, and military equipment resulting in 99.8% operational readiness across the entire dining facility.
- Monitored the level of supplies in a dining facility to ensure purchases are made in timely manner.
- Ensured that the inspection of equipment is renewed before it expires to avoid any legal issues.
- Maintained equipment records for over \$2M+ of equipment and scheduled all necessary maintenance to keep it operational.
- Accomplished 100% inspection of every equipment every two weeks to avoid mechanical failure.
- Installed property book and supported data in the AFMIS system.

US Army, Inventory Manager at Army Dining Facility, JBLM, WA

Jan 2016 - Sep, 2016

Monitored the receipt, storage, redistribution, and accountability of merchandise worth \$100,000 and performed leadership skill to train my teammates about management skill to promote efficient efficiency of operations.

- **Award winning:** Awarded Certificate of excellence for best Inventory Manager due to overseeing and controlling of ordering and saves rations worth of \$100,000.
- Supervised and performed duties involving request, receipt, storage, issue, accountability, and preservation of over \$100,000 worth of food.
- Performed inventory reconciliation by investigating and resolving discrepancies, initiating inventory comparisons, making recommendations in denials and cancellations, and following up on redistribution orders.
- Managed entire inventory and operated the Army food service facility utilizing AFMIS system.
- Attested orders upon receipt with order I generated from AFMIS (Army Food Management Information System) for accuracy.
- Monitored the ration storage areas on a routine basis to determine if rations are being used in a timely manner.
- Ensured the product stock is adequate to cover demand of customers.
- Analyzed storage level report against production schedules for Actual use vs Projected use.

US Army, Administrative Professionals at Army dining facility, JBLM, WA

Feb 2015 – Dec, 2015

Served as administrative assistant to the Dining Facility, providing a wide variety of administrative and clerical duties involved in the overall operation of the dining facility.

- Analyzed budgets records, and review financial transactions in order to ensure that expenditures are within the budget.
- · Verified all dining facility subsistence requests and ensured all established standards are followed.
- Maintained accountability of sensitive and high dollar food items.
- Performed weekly and monthly inventories and ensured accountability is kept within tolerance limitations.
- Established energy conservation, safety, security, and headcount standard operating procedures (SOPs), delivering production schedules, ration requests, and monthly personnel reports.
- Monitored compliance with health and fire regulations regarding food preparation and serving, and building maintenance.
- Ensured all headcount documents are closed out, annotated and filed appropriately.
- Reviewed menus, work sheets and recipes and determined types and quantities of items required for number of persons to be served.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree in Science, University of Maryland University College, Adelphi, MD

Graduated May 2018

Microsoft Software & Systems Academy (MSSA) | Computer Science (CS) Certification, Saint Martin's University, Lacey, WA December 2017

- Concentration: Server & Cloud Administration
- 18 semester credit hours of course work which can be applied to a Bachelor's in Computer Science.
- Equivalent to a minor in Computer Science at Saint Martin's University.
- MSSA training and certification.

TRAINING

Microsoft Software System Academy (MSSA)

Linux (Independent Learning)

Networking (Independent Learning)

CERTIFICATIONS

- MTA Networking Fundamentals- Certified 2017
- MTA Windows Server Administration Fundamentals- Certified 2017
- MTA Database Fundamentals- Certified 2017
- ISM